Morning, Dwight.
Who are you?
Who am I? I'm Jim.
We've been working
together for 12 years.
Weird joke, Dwight.
You're not Jim.
Jim's not Asian.
You seriously never noticed?
Hey, hats off to you
for not seeing race.
All right then, Jim.
Why don't you tell me
about that sale that
you made yesterday?
Uh... Wellington Systems?
Sold them 10 cases of
24-pound letter stock.
Or were you talking
about Krieger-Murphy?
Because I didn't
close that one yet,
but I'm hoping
I've got a voicemail
from Paul Krieger
waiting for me.
Please enter your password.
You have one new message.
How did you know?
No, no.
That is sensitive
information, only for
employees, not outsiders!
Dwight, cut it out.
I'm trying to work.
You don't work here!
You're not Jim!
Jim, I got us that
dinner reservation.
Grico's, 7:30.
Oh! Great. Can't wait.
Jim's at the dentist
this morning,
and Steve is
an actor friend of ours.
I don't know who you are,
but you are not Jim!
This is Jim!
Um...
Oh, dear.
How did...
Hey! Study buddies!
Oh! Okay.
Oh!
Getting Things Done.
Awesome!
It's all about finding ways to
make yourself more efficient.
Life hacking, baby.
This morning,
I brushed my
teeth in the shower.
Saved myself 90 seconds,
which I just used to
explain this to you.
Damn it.
Since Andy promoted me to
assistant regional manager,
I've been trying to step
my game up, you know,
be more productive.
In fact, you know what?
Let's knock out a few more
of these sound bites
while we're here.
Whoa. That person
has really gotten
him or herself
into quite a predicament.
Ah, French. It's a
great language if you're
a chain-smoking acrobat.
I'm just trying
to fit in better
with Andy's family.
They all speak more
than one language,
usually when I'm there.
You want to learn
a really impressive
second language, try Dothraki.
Win over any man in my guild.
Dothraki is the native tongue
of the nomadic, war-mongering
horse lords of Essos,
as featured in the superb
Home Box Office series
Game of Thrones.
It has a lot of nudity,
which I fast forward
through to get to the
chopped-off heads.
I could teach you if you want.
It's a lot easier than French.
Yeah. Let's do it!
Oh!
It means, "Excellent."
And we have begun.
Is everything okay?
Mmm.
Oh. Oh. Yeah, yeah.
Fine, fine. I mean I...
I just don't want to
burden you with my
massive stress freakout.
Great.
It's just that I am taking
my driver's license
test in two days,
and I need to practice
with an experienced
driver in the car.
But I've had no time
to do that,
thanks to "DemAndy."
I just want to
hit the open road
and drive, man!
But in whose car?
Nellie!
Get your wrinkly
old balls in here!
Nellie, I could practice with
you in my car at lunchtime.
Oh, Pam, thank you!
You are my savior!
Oh, my gosh!
Oh!
I'm sorry,
I'm leaving you
alone for lunch.
Don't worry about it.
I have a thing,
a thing of soup,
which I've been
wanting to try.
This is my research
into how we might
produce childproof paper
that doesn't
give you papercuts.
We can't.
And here is a printout
of your genealogy
from ThislsYourFamilyTree.com.
Executive-summary me.
Hit the highlights.
Well, it turns out
you are a distant blood
relative of Michelle Obama.
As in?
Wife of Barack,
loves gardening,
wants to wipe
out fat children.
Wow.
This is super flattering.
She's the most popular
person in America.
This is a big
day for both of us.
My fellow Americans!
I have a feeling
my approval rating
is about to go
through the roof.
It turns out I am
related to Michelle Obama.
I was intimidated by
Andy's family before,
and now I have to see
the First Lady at holidays?
She's going to be like,
"What's your stance
on politics?"
Or, "What is the
best war to do?"
And I will just be like...
Duh...
All right,
we've got to get rid
of all this junk food.
Get fit, America.
Not sure if the buzz
has reached the annex yet,
but I'm related
to Michelle Obama.
Yeah, we noticed
early on that Andy really
appreciates enthusiasm.
So we decided the
best way to get ahead here
is to be his cheerleaders.
Whoa!
It's starting to have
this reverse effect, though,
where I really do think
the stuff he does is awesome.
Yeah, me, too. It's weird.
Hard to remember
what's real at this point.
Just clap
through it, man.
You log in sales at
10 different times.
If you log them all at once,
you'd save a lot of time.
It's called batching.
This is really good, Darryl.
Life hacking, man.
There he is!
Andy, you've got
to check this out.
He just showed me what...
Right now I need
canned tuna, okay?
Darryl, guess which
talented individual,
who also has
a killer singing voice,
is related
to the First Lady.
Tracee Ellis Ross,
daughter of the First Lady
of Motown, Diana Ross.
It's me.
I'm related
to Michelle Obama.
What? Really?
I mean,
it's distant, but...
That's cool, man.
Right?
Darryl said, "Cool, man."
He called me a cool man.
You know, I really do
think it'd be worth it to
pull over and just
take 10 minutes to eat.
The thing is, Pam,
I'm going to be eating
while I'm driving,
so I might
as well get good at it.
Brake lights. Brake lights!
Brake lights! Brake lights!
Whoo!
I'm just saying,
what does it imply,
in this country,
when a white person
shares an ancestor
with a black person?
You think that Andy's
family owned slaves?
Well, somebody
owned somebody.
And I don't think anybody
would buy an Andy.
"I throat-rip."
"You throat-rip."
"He/she/it throat-rips."
More of a barbaric growl.
Louder!
You're shouting it from
the back of a horse!
Pretty crazy about
Andy and Michelle Obama, huh?
Yeah.
It's almost unbelievable.
What?
Well, you know
how Andy has been
really salting
my onions lately?
Sure.
Well, when he
asked me to look up
his ancestry online,
I remembered that
news story about
Michelle Obama
having white relatives,
and I just knew he
would eat that up.
So, he's not related
to Michelle Obama?
Pam, I barely know
how to turn on my computer.
Nellie's pretty fearless,
and I think she might
be maybe even
almost sort of fun.
Pam!
Well, if there's
another explanation,
I don't really see
what it could possibly be.
What's going on here?
I'm related to
the First Lady, okay?
Get over it.
I still need weekly
status reports from
most of you.
So, can we get
back to work, please?
Get back to work.
Andy?
Andy, no! I would be
very polite today.
Why?
Is it Employees' Day
or something?
I cannot keep track
of these BS holidays.
Your connection
to Michelle Obama
has certain
negative connotations.
Most likely, your
family were slave owners.
Does anyone else think
it's possible that
I come from slave owners?
Whoa. That person
has really gotten
him or herself into
quite a predicament.
Hey, Mom, it's Andy.
Give me a call
when you get a chance,
got a quick
question for you.
No big deal, it's just about
America's national shame.
Thanks, bye.
Where were we?
Yes, okay,
your productivity thing.
Yes, yes, yes.
Great. Ooh!
Spreadsheets. Yum, yum.
I included some
time-saving ideas.
Uh-huh, uh-huh. Look,
I'm not going to lie to you.
I'm a teensy bit
distracted right now.
Look, Andy, even if
your ancestors did
own slaves,
it wouldn't
be your fault.
This is only weird
if you make it weird.
Right on, brother.
Word dat.
Does anyone here have
fermented mare's milk?
Hey, Erin.
Oh. Okay. Sorry.
Aw, still, it must be great
to have something else
going on outside of work.
Yeah.
Turn signal.
It's exciting
to be painting again.
Those are the wipers.
So, it's just,
there you go. Yeah.
Yeah, things get so
busy with the kids,
red light,
that it's nice to
have a creative outlet.
Red light!
Red! Red!
That is brilliant, Pam!
I would love to see
some of your work.
Well, since we're
stopped at a light,
here is the mural
I did for Angela's baby.
That is amazing, Pam.
Oh, I love the lion
in the tuxedo.
Angela insisted that all
the animals be fully clothed.
Hey, has anyone
turned in their status
reports up here?
So, no?
Do you think
maybe you could
remind people?
I'm trying to
downplay the whole
bossy boss thing today.
Because of your slaves. Yep.
Not my slaves,
my ancestors' maybe.
Probably not.
Oh. Well, if it makes
you feel any better,
the Dothraki word
for slavemaster...
...is a term of respect.
I'm learning how
to speak Dothraki!
Color you impressed.
That you're learning
a made-up language from
HBO's Game of Thrones?
I have a lot going on today,
but this was a great nerd-out.
Dwight! You didn't tell me
you were teaching me
a fake language.
People laughed at
Klingon at first,
and now you can major in it.
Hi, guys.
Hey, boss, I am so thirsty.
Can I have a scoop of water?
Yeah, you don't
have to ask me.
Okay, great.
Very funny, I get it.
Just because my
ancestors happen to be...
Very funny, Kevin.
Change my ringtone.
Very funny.
I liked the original
song on my ringtone,
which you may remember,
was Diamonds on
the Soles of Her Shoes,
by Paul Simon,
featuring Ladysmith,
African American Mambazo.
Good. Very good.
Oh! No!
Here, it's a text
from Andy.
"New special proj.
Need fam. tree
for evbody.
"Really dig up dirt ASAP."
And then in parentheses,
he wrote out,
"As soon as possible."
Oh, God.
Looks like it's
pretendy time again.
Write back,
"Looking for dirt."
Oh. Can I help? We could
say someone is related
to, um, Tonya Harding?
Pam, I'm related
to Tonya Harding.
Oh, gee, I'm...
No, I'm just practicing
my lying.
I love it!
Brilliant.
What should
we say about Jim?
Um, oh! I'll say he's
related to Richard Nixon!
It's an inside joke.
He looks really
Nixon-y when he wakes up.
My ex behaved like Nixon.
All of the lying, none of
the sexual charisma.
I just made a joke then.
I'm sorry. It's just, um,
I actually do have this weird
feeling that there's something
Jim isn't telling me.
Oh, no. An affair,
it is always an affair.
Jim? No.
How can you be sure?
Because he just
loves me too much.
You're a cocky little
thing, aren't you, Pam?
I've done a little
genealogy research
of my own.
Turns out I'm
not the only one with
a few skeletons
in the old family closet.
For example, Phyllis'
great-great-grandmother was
responsible for
spreading cholera
to the United States.
Ew.
Kevin is related to both
John Wayne Gacy and
John Wayne Bobbitt.
And John Wayne?
No, not that I see here.
Wayne Johnson? The Rock?
You mean Dwayne, and no.
What about Jim Halpert?
Uh-oh! Turns out,
distant relative of the
reviled Richard Nixon.
Pam always says
I look like Nixon.
That's crazy, right?
I mean, there's nothing there.
True.
Oh, no.
Dwight's grandfather...
Was a member
of the Bund,
which is not technically
the same thing
as the
Nazi party. So...
I was going to say
he was a tax evader.
Oh.
I was joking about
that whole Bund thing.
The look on your faces.
And Meredith
is a blood relative
of Lizzie Borden.
Cool.
Stop it! Stop it!
You're frightening me.
Andy, did you
call this meeting
just to talk junk
about our families?
Yeah, that,
you're being
really mean.
Stop it, Andy.
No, I'm proving
a point, okay?
We all have ancestors
who may have done horrible
things in the past,
but it's in the past,
and it's not our fault,
so we don't have
to talk about it.
The difference is, Andy,
that you're the only one
here still benefitting
from the terrible things
your ancestors did.
Might have done,
and how do you figure?
Your family is rich.
I have to believe that
a big part of
the Bernard fortune
was earned
on the backs of slaves.
You know, there's
nothing wrong with being
successful in America, Oscar.
I'm not going
to apologize for
my family's wealth.
That wealth could one day
benefit society,
if capital gains are ever
taxed at the same
rate as earned income.
Okay, Kevin did that.
I do not wish I was in Dixie.
Hey, Mom.
How are you?
Did any Bernards
ever own a plantation
in the South?
She said, "No." Take that!
Follow-up question,
did any Bernards ever
make money in an unsavory way?
I just asked you...
Why didn't you
just say that?
Okay, stop. Stop.
Stop talking! Stop talking!
That's... No,
I don't want to know that.
Okay.
You're interrupting a meeting.
I have to go. Love you. Bye.
Well, it turns out
the Bernards of yore
did not own slaves.
Really?
We merely transported them,
which at worst makes
us amoral middlemen.
Yo, D-Dog. I need your help.
I'm trying to think
of things I can say that
make it sound like
I had a more difficult
childhood than I actually had.
You're going to po' mouth.
Exactly! Help me
"po' mouth," Darryl.
Actually, Andy,
you promised me five minutes
to talk about
productivity suggestions.
What if I said
that my dad beat me,
and I just left out
the croquet of it all?
Or I could just go
all the way and say
I grew up in an apartment.
Or is that too crazy?
That could work.
You know, Darryl,
this is textbook
assistant regional manager
stuff here, and I feel like
I'm doing all
the heavy lifting.
I'm coming up with
all the ideas here.
I'm going for a walk.
Okay.
Good, good, and...
You doing
all right, man?
I'm done.
I got to get
out of here.
Yeah, not the easiest
day to be assistant
regional manager.
It's not just today,
it's every day.
Seems like
the better title I have,
the stupider my job gets.
Well, come on.
It can always
get better, right?
Hmm. Yeah, right.
No, I'm serious.
There's always
something better.
Like what?
Like, hypothetically,
if I said that there
was another job that
you and I could both have.
What kind of job?
Something cool,
like sports marketing, or...
Does that sound like
something you'd be into?
Hell, yeah.
Right?
That sounds awesome.
Okay. But wait,
what if I told you
that it was in Philly?
So you'd have to...
I love Philly.
Right?
That's not
even a thought.
Not even a thought.
It's not even that far away.
I could still commute.
Exactly. Exactly!
All right.
What? Wait, wait, wait!
So what, is this happening?
Oh, it's happening.
Let's just keep it between
you and me for right now.
Yeah. For sure, for sure,
for sure. Man.
And Pam's into it?
Yeah, we haven't
talked about it,
but I think
that she's...
I think she understands.
Aw, come on, man.
I thought you
had something real.
What? No, no, no.
Come on.
This is real.
It's not real until
your wife is on board.
So what did you
want to show me?
That is quite
an ugly wall, isn't it?
Yeah.
It's really ugly.
It needs something,
doesn't it?
I'm thinking a mural.
You mean me?
Yes, you! You are so talented.
It's going to be my
next special project,
hiring Scranton's
most dangerous
young muralist
to paint
the warehouse wall.
Oh, my God, I love it.
Nellie, this is brilliant!
Hey!
Hey. Can I talk to
you for a second?
Anything you
have to say to her,
you can say to me.
She never loved you!
What? No,
I... I got this.
It's okay.
This is his fault.
It is not your fault.
I'm going to find
you someone better
and rich.
And Filipino, but we'll
break that to her later.
You know what
this is all about?
Yeah. You, too, huh?
Yeah.
Go on, spill it!
Tell her all the gory
details, you snake!
Hey, he deserves this,
and he said I could
get in on it, too.
Yeah.
Oh, Pam, no! Oh,
I can't bear to watch this.
I don't know what
I was so worried about.
I have the best
wife in the world.
I still can't believe
he didn't tell me.
I was helping
Nellie drive, and...
Do not care.
I like that guy.
We should hook him
up with Meredith.
Ooh.